製作: 星際迷航中國字幕組 (https://www.startrekchina.org)
翻譯: 在爬牆的鬍子 & NCC1015 & EnterpriseH & 舟行萬里1234 & Bruce & 凌塔
校對: narwhrl
時軸: narwhrl
特效: narwhrl
日期: 2025-07-28
《星際迷航: 新世界》前情提要
Previously on Star Trek: Strange New Worlds...
艾麗卡傷勢嚴重 但傷情穩定了
Erica is critical, but stable.
我到現在都覺得像是在做夢
Still doesn't feel totally real.
我本該死了的
I should be dead.
我還活著只是僥天之幸
I'm on borrowed time.
我還沒準備好和你分別
I'm not ready to let you go.
達克'拉赫將軍
General Dak'Rah.
我知道你和查普爾都曾駐紮在加戈爾上
I know you and Chapel were both stationed on J'Gal,
拉赫就是在那裡成名的
where Rah earned his reputation.
姆'本加 我來這裡是為了給你提供療癒
M'Benga, I'm here to provide healing.
把你的手從我身上拿開
Get your hands off me! Don't!
不是我先動手的
I didn't start the fight.
但我很高興他死了
But I'm glad he's dead.
艦長個人日誌
Captain's personal log,
星曆2449.1
stardate 2449.1.
進取號要去完成一個常規掃描任務
Enterprise has embarked on a routine scanning mission,
這給了我和瑪麗一些額外的相處時間
giving Marie and me some time
她很快就要去
to enjoy our last few days together
新的船上任職了
before her new commission.
我才剛習慣她的裝飾風格
I was just getting used to her decorating choices,
但一位艦長終歸是屬於她自己的船的
but a captain belongs on her own ship.
我們原本以為
We had every reason to believe
那些難以捉摸的戈恩組織已完全萎縮
the evasive Gorn tissue was in full remission.
但不幸的是 它們復發了
But, unfortunately, it's returned.
而且呈現出高度侵襲性
And it's aggressive.
但是情況也不是完全無望
And yet, hope is not lost.
奇美拉之花
The Chimera Blossom.
一個珍稀品種
A rare specimen,
因其獨特的生物特性而備受追捧
long sought-after for its biological uniqueness.
這種花 可以治好她嗎
This flower-- it can help her?
希望渺茫 克里斯
It's a long shot, Chris.
但據傳
But it is rumored
其中含有一種特殊化合物
to contain a chemical compound
這種化合物普遍擁有
that is universal in its ability
協助入侵分子穿透細胞膜的能力
to move invasive molecules through cell membranes.
也許能遏制惡性腫瘤
Could stop the malignancy.
爭取治療的時間
Buying us time.
為什麼我嗅到了弦外之音
Why am I sensing a caveat?
正如史波克所說 它很稀有
Well, like Spock said, it's rare.
我們已經找到了一處
And we've tracked down the one place
有可能長有奇美拉之花的地方
the Chimera is likely to be found.
在一個叫肯佛瑞的星球
It's a planet called Kenfori.
肯佛瑞?
Kenfori?
那整個星系都禁止通航
That whole system is a no-fly zone.
是啊 確實
Yeah, that's true.
但是那裡原先有一個
But it was once the location
星聯的科研設施
of a Federation research facility,
主要致力於新興地區農業研究
focused mainly on frontier farming,
特別是作物長效培育技術
specifically crop longevity.
後來在戰爭初期 那裡被克林貢占領了
The Klingons invaded at the start of the war
我們的所有權有了爭議
and our claim fell into dispute.
戰爭結束之後 雙方都同意放棄爭奪此地
After the war ended, both sides agreed to give it up.
所以這不僅是個禁航區域
So it's not just a no-fly zone.
還是個限制區域
It's the restricted zone.
我們去那裡的話
We can't go anywhere near it
會違反一堆外交條約
without violating multiple treaties.
我告訴過他們這個主意簡直瘋了 克里斯
Told them it was crazy, Chris.
我不會讓大家為了我一個人冒這麼大的風險
I won't allow people to take risks like this for me.
我更不會眼睜睜地看著你死
I won't watch you die.
如果這種花能救治你 我們就要拿到它
If this blossom will help you, we are going to get it.
但是
But
星際艦隊肯定不會批准這種事
Starfleet will never authorize this.
我們得偷偷地幹這件事
This has to be completely off the books.
所以我們提議派一個小型外勤隊去
That is why we propose a minimal away team.
就姆'本加醫生和我去就行
Just Dr. M'Benga and myself.
計劃挺好
Good plan.
只需做一處調整
With one adjustment.
看吧 要來了
Here it comes.
如果必須得有人為此違規 那也得是我
If anyone's going to break the rules, it's going to be me.
早就說他會這樣了吧
Told them that, too.
我很感激你自願參與任務 史波克先生
I appreciate you stepping up Mr. Spock,
但是如果我們被發現了 責任在我
but if we're caught, the responsibility falls on me.
別小看我啊 艦長
You insult me, Captain.
他從來沒被發現過
He never gets caught.
我從來沒被發現過
I never get caught.
斯坎內爾中尉
Lieutenant Scannell,
請把肯佛瑞星系周圍
please pull up cartography
緩衝帶的星圖調取出來
on the buffer zone around the Kenfori system.
看起來條約劃定的分界線
Looks like the treaty line is
正處於一片巨型星塵帶的邊緣
on the edge of a giant dust belt.
我已經很久沒有飛進過
Been a long time since I've flown
有爭議的克林貢星域了
into disputed Klingon territory.
是路過有爭議的克林貢星域
Around disputed Klingon territory.
進取號不會跨越分界線
Enterprise will not cross that line.
一旦穿梭機飛進星塵帶
Once the shuttle clears that dust belt,
個人通訊將徹底中斷
personal comms will be down.
我們可以通過凍結所有通訊信號
We can maintain their cover by freezing all other
來給他們打掩護
communications as well.
我會設置一個加密的艦對艦頻道
I'm setting up an encrypted ship-to-ship channel
這樣艦長就能和我們保持聯絡
for the captain to check in on the hour.
不需要我提醒你們
I do not need to remind you
一旦穿梭機被發現 會有什麼後果吧
of the consequences if our away team's shuttle is discovered.
奧特加斯 我們出發吧
Ortegas, take us out.
有趣的部分來了
Now comes the fun part.
顯擺
Show-off.
歡迎大家盡情誇獎 鼓掌喝彩
I'll accept any and all accolades and applause
小費我也收哦
and tips.
承認吧 你們都懷念我精湛的駕駛技術
Admit it. You all missed my fancy flying.
我們確實懷念
We did, actually.
就像騎自行車一樣
Like riding a bike.
只不過這自行車用的核聚變引擎
With fusion-powered thrusters.
我以為你可恨我的飛行技術了
And all this time I thought you hated my flying.
你還記得在波瑞利斯ζ星那次嗎
You remember Zeta Borealis?
穿梭機落地的一瞬間
The moment our shuttle landed,
你一腳踢開防爆門
you kicked open those storm doors
當場嘔吐了起來
and you threw up.
如果我沒記錯的話 那是因為我們之前
If memory serves, it was those Vedalan cigars
抽了維達蘭雪茄的緣故
we smoked the night before.
不過說實話 那些維達蘭人辦的派對真是一絕
Well, those Vedalans knew how to throw a party, let's be honest.
絕對的
Oh, definitely
即使事後頭疼都值了
worth the headache.
在我們行進的路線上有一個物體
Oh, there's an object in our path.
成分無法確定
Indeterminate composition.
星塵帶有干擾 沒法掃描
Can't get a reading in this dust belt.
戰爭期間 這種地方布滿了雙方布下的
During the war this area would have been teeming with mines.
太空雷陣
Federation and Klingon.
但是根據條約 空雷應該被排除了才對
Per the treaty, they should have all been swept.
也許他們遺漏了一個
Maybe they missed one.
我會與之保持距離 最好把護盾也升起來
I'll keep a distance. Better raise shields.
打開通訊系統
Turn on comms.
正在將通訊系統設置為克林貢常用頻段
Setting comms to common Klingon frequency range.
這是一個通訊信標
It's a communications beacon.
這裡有一條信息
Something's coming through.
你見過這個嗎
You ever see that before?
是啊 在戰爭期間見過
Yes, in the war.
我曾被派駐到一座被炸毀的克林貢礦場附近
I was once stationed near a bombed Klingon mine
那裡有嚴重的輻射危險
with radiation danger.
大致翻譯一下就是「要麼滾回去 要麼等死」
Loosely translated it means, "Go back or die."
但他們為什麼要在這裡放警示信標
But why leave a warning beacon here?
不管了
It doesn't matter.
我們沒有退路
Going back is not an option.
沒有生命跡象
No life signs.
所以這裡除了我們 沒別人
So we are all alone down here.
不 艦長
No, Captain,
我是說完全沒有生命體徵
I mean no life signs.
全是植物 沒有動物
All flora, no fauna...
如此富饒的生物群落中沒有動物嗎
In a biome this rich?
這裡肯定有地方存在著動物
There must be animal life here somewhere.
算了 至少我們是來找植物的
Well, at least the flora's all that matters.
你看到下山路上的那個湖了嗎
You see that lake on the way down?
看到了 非常適合飛釣
Ah, perfect for fly-fishing.
是啊 要是我們沒有在執行任務
Yeah, if we weren't always on a mission.
而且還得有動物能上鈎才行
And if there was something alive to catch.
有道理
Fair point.
那應該就是我們的研究站了
That must be our research facility.
根據克莉絲汀的研究
Christine's research suggests
他們應該會把那種花的樣本保存在內
they would have kept samples of the flower inside.
至少我們不用把整片森林翻個遍了
At least we don't have to scour this whole forest.
所以 你怎麼看科爾比和克里斯汀這對情侶
So, what do you think of this whole Korby-Christine thing?
哦 克里斯
Ah, Chris,
要我提醒你 我離過三次婚嗎
do I have to remind you I have three ex-wives?
準確來說是四個
Well, four, technically.
那一次不算
That was an annulment.
不過下一位嘛
But the next one...
醫者可以自醫嗎
Physician heal thyself?
我更願意說 我還在不斷進步中
I like to consider myself a work in progress.
有生命跡象了嗎
Life sign?
恰恰相反
The opposite.
陣亡的士兵嗎
War casualty?
不是
No.
戰鬥中不可能會有這種創傷
You don't see these wounds in battle.
他的胸腔被整個剖開了
His rib cage has been split open.
挨了不止一發相位槍
Not a single phaser burn.
從腐爛程度來看
Given the rate of decay,
我判斷他是在撤離之後死去的
I'd say he died after the evacuation.
像是被什麼動物殺死的
Killed by some kind of animal maybe?
只是
Only...
這裡沒有動物
Only no life signs.
會是早已離開的動物嗎
An animal that's long gone?
最好不要冒這個險
Better not risk it.
相位槍準備
Phasers.
備用能源還在運作著
Auxiliary power's still on.
十分微弱
Barely.
這裡發生的事情真是令人遺憾
It's a shame what happened here.
戰爭奪走了一切
The war took everything.
這個是奇美拉之花嗎
Chimera Blossoms?
親眼所見 果然更驚艷
Even more beautiful in person.
得來全不費功夫啊
Didn't have to look far, huh?
別靠近
Wait.
你的背包裡有一個面罩
There's a set of these in your bag.
尋找那些盛開的花朵
Look for the ones in full bloom.
但不要用皮膚直接接觸它們
But don't touch them with bare skin.
這些到底是什麼
What exactly are these?
只是預防措施而已
It's just a precaution.
劑量不當的話 藥物也可能具有毒性
At improper doses, the medication can be toxic.
某些有機毒物具有藥用價值
Certain organic poisons have medicinal value.
幾個世紀以來 醫生們用這些
Doctors have used them for centuries
來治療心臟疾病
to treat heart disease,
瘧疾
malaria...
這能讓她維持多久
How long will this give her?
你知道 任何船員的病情和治療情況
You know the condition and treatment of any crew member
都是保密的
is confidential
除非他們會對其他船員構成威脅
unless they jeopardize the rest of the crew.
我不是在以艦長的身份問你
Not as your captain.
而是以一個朋友的身份
As your friend.
以瑪麗的
As Marie's...
我需要知道
I need to know.
她有希望完全康復嗎
I-Is there a chance that she can really be saved?
這是她唯一康復的機會了
This is her only chance.
就在昨天 我們束手無策的時候
Just yesterday, we were out of options,
史波克又找到了一個治療方案
but Spock found one more.
一份希望
One to hope for.
克里斯 奮力一搏的機會
A fighting chance, Chris.
檢測到一股輕微的電磁波動
Picking up a minor EM flux
正朝著肯佛瑞方向移動
moving towards Kenfori.
坐標 第八扇區 方位角15-29-4
Coordinates: Section Eight, mark 15-29-4.
傳感器顯示其在以一個不規則的運動軌跡移動
Sensors show it is moving in an irregular pattern.
這表明這是一種自然發生的現象
That suggests it's a naturally occurring phenomenon.
對於塵埃帶來說很正常
Normal for a dust belt.
收到 繼續觀察第九扇區
Copy. Continue to Section Nine.
長官 我提議對第八扇區進行二次掃描
Commander, I would like to recommend a secondary scan
這一回濾除電磁信號
of Section Eight, one that filters out EM rays.
我有預感
I've got a hunch.
安全點總沒錯
Better safe than sorry.
斯坎內爾中尉
Lieutenant Scannell?
重新掃描第八扇區
Rescanning Section Eight.
確認在電磁波動後方存在中微子輻射
Confirming neutrino emissions behind the flux.
正在檢測曲速信號
Checking for a warp signature.
是一艘克林貢戰列巡洋艦
It's a Klingon battle cruiser.
戰爭期間 他們經常使用電磁干擾
In the war they used to mask their ships
來掩蓋他們的曲速信號
behind bursts of EM radiation.
幹得漂亮 上尉
Good call, Lieutenant.
這改變不了什麼
This doesn't change a thing.
我們繼續保持在此監視他們
We continue monitoring from here
直到我們有理由接近
until we have reason not to.
中校 他們選擇現在露面
Commander, it's a pretty big coincidence
是個巨大的巧合
that they choose now to show up.
要是他們發現了艦長的穿梭機怎麼辦
What if they spotted the captain's shuttle?
或許吧
Maybe.
但克林貢人算不上有多遵守條約
But Klingons aren't famous for abiding by treaty.
他們可能只是來打撈殘骸的
These could just be scavengers.
我不喜歡在沒有證據的情況下妄下結論
I hate to assume causation where there isn't any.
烏乎拉 通訊上監聽到什麼東西嗎
Uhura, any comms chatter?
沒有 長官 所有通訊頻段都處於靜默狀態
Negative, sir, across all channels.
外面安靜得像圖書館一樣
It's quiet as a library out there.
有變化的話向我報告
Let me know if that changes.
現在 我們要沉住氣
For now... we'll sit tight.
這些傷口與外面那些
These wounds are consistent with
克林貢人遺骸上的傷口相符
those Klingon remains outside.
有什麼東西在同時殺害人類和克林貢人嗎
Something was killing both humans and Klingons?
如果可以稱之為殺害的話
If you can call it that.
這更像是生吞活剝
More like devouring.
走吧 我們已經拿到需要的東西了
Come on. We got what we came for.
撤退吧
Let's go.
那肯定是個活物
That had to be alive.
是發生故障的實驗室設備
Malfunctioning lab equipment.
我還是沒有檢測到任何生命信號
I'm still not getting any life signs.
不會吧
Humor me.
什麼都沒有
Nothing.
我們的穿梭機
Our shuttle.
有可能他們不知道我們的存在
It's possible they don't know about us.
現在他們知道了
They know about us.
人類的惡臭在空氣中瀰漫不散
他們離得不遠了
省著點用
留著能量對付他們
三錄儀給我
他們說上去的人沒一個能活著回來
準備好為榮譽赴死了嗎
這是場狩獵派對
It's a hunting party.
他們像獵斯克拉兔子一樣在追我們
They're chasing us like Skral rabbits.
如果我們被抓住了
If we're captured,
他們肯定也很樂意把我們做成標本
they'll want to make examples of us.
我猜兩條路都一樣
I'm sure the other direction was equally as bad.
你知道他們看到了就會開槍
You know they'll shoot on sight.
那我們就先開槍
Then we shoot first.
擊暈擋
On stun.
快跑
Run.
撤退
你給我打的是安慰劑嗎
Are you hitting me with placebo right now?
你的身體已經適應了止痛藥
Your body has acclimated to the pain inhibitors.
查普爾護士應該可以
Nurse Chapel should...
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
巴特爾艦長
Captain Batel.
我理解您的不適在加劇
I understand your discomfort has increased.
史波克
Spock.
還用你說
You think?
瓦肯人有一種古代技藝
Vulcans have an ancient technique
能通過冥想來調節疼痛
of regulating pain through meditation.
經過練習 人類也可以掌握
With practice, humans can do it, too.
儘管如此 要達到我認為您需要的水平
However, achieving a level I suspect you need
需要的時間是我們等不起的
will take time we do not have.
查普爾護士建議我來引導您
Nurse Chapel has suggested I guide you through it
借助心靈融合的形式 如果您願意的話
using a form of mind meld, if you consent.
什麼都行
Pretty much anything.
吾思即汝思
My mind to your mind.
同呼吸共命運
One breath between us.
無論你在做什麼 請繼續
Whatever you're doing, keep doing.
是您的自尊心承受著痛苦
Your ego holds the pain.
讓您的思想放下自尊心
Let your mind release your ego,
這樣或許可以減輕您的痛苦
so it may eclipse your suffering.
史波克
Spock!
快醒醒
Snap out of it!
史波克 放開她 是我啊
Let go of her, Spock. It's me.
克里斯汀
It's Christine.
我似乎暫時情緒失控了
I seem to have temporarily lost control.
那還用說
You sure did.
瑪麗 你還好嗎
Marie, are-are you okay?
還好
Yeah.
發生什麼了
What happened?
當我們心靈融合的時候 我吸納了您的痛苦
When we joined minds, I absorbed your pain.
但我也
But I also...
我看到了什麼
I saw something.
是的 我也是
Yes, as did I.
它感覺既像是您的一部分 又不是
It felt both a part of you and not.
是戈恩嗎
Was it Gorn?
這可能嗎
Is that even possible?
恐怕我兩個問題都無法回答 艦長
I am afraid I do not have the answer to either question, Captain.
謝謝你 史波克先生
Thank you, Mr. Spock.
我現在好多了
The pain is much better now.
史波克少校
Lieutenant Spock,
金萊利中校命令全體高級軍官到待命室報到
Commander Chin-Riley needs all senior officers in the ready room.
我很快就來
I will be there momentarily.
不好意思 少尉
My apologies, Ensign.
我們可能有麻煩了
We may have a situation.
外勤隊沒有在預定的時間和我們通訊
Our away team failed to check in at the prescheduled time.
他們兩人的應答器都開著
Their transponders are both active,
但不回應我們從進取號發出的任何呼叫
but they are not responding to any hails from the Enterprise,
換句話說
which means
要麼是他們的通訊器出了問題
they're either having comms trouble or...
要麼人出了什麼事
something else happened.
中尉
Lieutenant.
佩利亞中校有時間親自前來參會嗎
Does Commander Pelia plan to grace us with her presence?
呃 她沒空
She, uh,
所以派我來了
got delayed and sent me.
好藉口 我知道她不喜歡開會
Nice try. I know she hates these meetings.
請坐
Sit.
我們需要在不引起克林貢人注意的前提下
We need to get within emergency beaming range
進入緊急傳送機的工作範圍
without attracting any Klingon attention.
我推薦緩慢接近
I recommend a slow approach.
以低脈衝推力航行能將我們
Flying at low impulse will keep us
隱藏在碎片帶運動的背景噪聲下
below the noise limit of debris motion.
他們的傳感器將無法
Their sensors will not be able
區分我們和星塵顆粒
to tell us apart from the dust particles.
那就是說我們只能以低脈衝推力航行
Well, we'd have to move at a fraction of impulse
而且還要關掉所有非必要系統
and shut down all nonessential systems.
但如果能讓我們隱形 那倒也值得
But if we were invisible, might be worth it.
根據我的估算 我們將需要四個小時到達肯佛瑞星
By my calculations, we would reach Kenfori in four hours.
這我能接受
I can live with that.
奧特加斯
Ortegas.
和史波克一起規劃一條航線
Plot a course with Mr. Spock.
四個小時
Four hours?
不 我不同意
Yeah, that won't work for me.
請說明 上尉
Explain yourself, Lieutenant.
我們幹嘛還要踮著腳躲著克林貢人
Why are we tiptoeing around these Klingons?
既然他們顯然已經知道姆'本加醫生和艦長在那了
It's obvious they know about the captain and Dr. M'Benga.
我們的當務之急應該是盡快把他們救出來
Our priority should be getting them out fast.
那你怎麼確保我們能夠在
And how do you propose we do that
不違反邊界條約的情況下做到這點
without violating a border treaty?
而且 假設
Hypothetically,
即便有可能接近
even if there were a way,
星塵帶的干擾
the interference from the dust belt
也會讓傳送機無法使用
makes transporting impossible.
我已經想到了個辦法可以同時解決這兩個問題
I've thought about both problems.
我們直接曲速進行星大氣熱層裡
We warp into the planet's thermosphere,
傳送完人 立馬曲速走 簡單
energize, and warp out, simple.
直接曲速進行星低軌道嗎
Warping into a low planetary orbit.
那很魯莽了
It's reckless.
你以前這麼幹過嗎
Have you ever done that?
還沒有
No.
但我能做到
But I could.
如此危險的機動極少有人嘗試
Such a dangerous maneuver is rarely attempted.
我估計高層大氣沒有問題
I could see the upper atmosphere maybe.
但我們只要沾到一點熱層的底
But if we scrape the bottom of the thermosphere,
船體就要被阻力扯成捲心菜瓣了
our hull would be shredded cabbage.
我不會讓這種事發生的
I won't let that happen.
此外 殘餘曲速場同樣會干擾傳送
Also, the residual warp field prohibits transport.
但在理論上 穿過局部曲速場
Well, in theory, one could lock in on a signal
建立傳送信號鎖定是可能的
through the residual field.
我沒有拆史波克先生的台的意思
Well, I don't mean to step on Mr. Spock's toes,
絕對沒有
of course, uh,
但只需要根據曲速場的空間扭曲程度
but you just have to calibrate the phase inducers
校準相位感應器
to the warp distortion.
當然 得非常快
Only, like, really fast.
就這樣
Yeah.
所以我的計劃全打鈎了
So my plan checks off all the boxes.
烏乎拉 有任何跡象表明
Uhura, is there any evidence
克林貢人知道外勤隊在地表嗎
the Klingons know about our people?
現在是完全的通訊靜默 一點聲音都沒有
Total comms silence out there, not even a whisper.
那麼史波克的計劃是最合理的
Then Spock's plan makes the most sense.
命令已經下達了
You have your orders.
真謝謝你啊 妮歐塔
Thanks a lot, Nyota.
我們是不是該談談奧特加斯上尉的事
Are we gonna discuss Lieutenant Ortegas?
她一直想做自己擅長的事
She was just doing her job.
我需要後備方案
I needed alternatives.
你說了算 但我想說
Your call, but, I mean,
她以前不像這樣
that wasn't like her.
她有時候可能很粗魯
She can be rude at times
但絕不會不服從
but not insubordinate.
會不會是太早讓她回歸崗位了
Could it be she's back on rotation too soon?
她已經過了心理關
She passed her psych eval.
畢竟就她的閱歷而言
And after all she went through,
她那有點毛躁的作風倒也在我的意料之中
I'm not surprised if she's a little rough around the edges.
拉安 你也明白的
You get that, La'An.
我們的傳感器壓根沒探測到這些東西
Not one of those things showed up on our sensors.
但它們看起來非常像活人
But they looked very alive to me.
至少 看起來不像死的
At least, you know, n-not... dead?
但無論它們是什麼
Whatever they are,
傳感器並不識別其為生命體徵
they don't register as life signs anymore.
除了我們 這裡死氣沉沉的
We are the only things moving in here.
這可是個藏身的好地方 看
This is as good a place as any to hole up. Look.
如果烏娜按部執行程序的話
If Una's following protocol,
進取號現在就在路上了
the Enterprise is already on its way.
我們要找個通訊器
We need to find comms,
複製進取號的加密頻道
clone the Enterprise's encrypted channel,
與他們協商一個撤離點
and then coordinate a rendezvous.
通信陣列
The comms array.
它在房頂
It's on the roof.
不行 上樓得和那些東西戰鬥
No, we'd have to engage with those...
不好聽點說 喪屍們?
For serious lack of a better word, zombies?
別這麼叫他們
Don't call them that.
他們曾經是聯邦的科學家
They were once Federation scientists.
和克林貢人
And Klingons.
聽著 我很想知道這兒究竟發生了什麼
Look, I'd really like to find out what happened here.
你可以調出實驗室的數據嗎
Can you recall the lab's data?
查普爾提到的作物
The crops that Chapel mentioned.
他們使用了奇美拉之花中的一種藥劑
They used an agent from the Chimera Blossom
並用多年生苔蘚的基因對其進行基因編輯
to modify them with genes from a perennial moss.
這種苔蘚可以在幾乎任何環境下生長
A moss that could live and grow anywhere.
它們會休眠 但並不會死亡
It lays dormant but never dies.
一種雜交超級作物
A hybrid supercrop.
哇 這樣一來能令許多聯邦殖民果腹
Wow. That would feed a lot of Federation colonists.
但事態在克林貢人入侵時急轉直下
Only things went to hell when the Klingons invaded.
他們攻擊了這裡
They attacked.
並無視了安全協議
With no regard for safety protocols.
設施中的每個人都被暴露其中
And everyone in the facility was exposed.
這導致苔蘚基因組滲入人體中
It inserted moss genomes into their bodies.
隨後 這種苔蘚吞噬了它周圍的所有植物
This moss consumes every plant around it...
以實現繁殖
to proliferate.
而這也是它們現在在做的
And now that is what they're doing.
吞噬一切活物
Devouring anything that breathes.
看來就是所謂的僵屍了
That sounds like the "Z" word.
等等 我們是不是也在吸著同樣的空氣
Wait, we're breathing that same air.
藥劑早就分解失效了
The agent would have broken down long ago.
現在我知道你看到奇美拉之花的時候
Now I see why you were so careful
為什麼要那麼小心了
about that Chimera Blossom.
別多想
Don't overthink it.
約瑟夫
Joseph...
為什麼瑪麗需要接受這樣的
why would Marie need biome engineering?
生物雜交工程
Hybridization?
史波克和我知道該如何安全使用它
Spock and I know how to use it safely.
好吧 回答我的問題
All right. Answer the question.
你想用什麼基因和她融合
You're gonna hybridize her with what?
克里斯 我不能
Chris, I cannot...
等等 不對勁
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
戈恩人?
The Gorn?
這就是你所謂的療法嗎
That's your miracle treatment?
你要把瑪麗變成什麼
You're g-going to turn Marie into a-a what?
一個人類和戈恩人的雜交種
A human-Gorn hybrid?
根本不是這樣
It is not that rudimentary.
那就解釋給我聽
Then explain it to me.
我跟你說過了
I already told you,
這是救活她的唯一方法
it is her only chance of survival.
讓我理解一下
Let me understand.
比起清除她身上的戈恩遺傳物質
Instead of ridding her body of the Gorn DNA,
現在反而要讓它永遠留在她體內
you're gonna make it permanent?
你想要對她進行基因改造
You're going to change her?
告訴我
Tell me!
約瑟夫
Joseph...
告訴我 你到底要對她做什麼
Just... what are you going to do to her?
這是她自己的選擇 克里斯
It was her decision, Chris.
她選擇如此
She chose this.
她不想讓你告訴我
She didn't want you to tell me.
所以史波克才主動提出和你一起去
That's why you and Spock wanted to go...
這樣一來我就永遠不會得知
So I would never know.
我的天
Oh, my...
這是救活她的唯一方法
This is the only way to save her.
而這也是我們都想要的結果
And that is what we all want.
這就是你救她的辦法嗎
This is your idea of saving--
還說什麼我們都想要的
Wh-What we all want?
絕對不是
No.
再復盤一下
Look again.
再努力努力
Try harder. I...
肯定有別的方法的
There's got to be another way.
她只有幾天時間了
She has a few days.
可能更少
Maybe less.
幾天
A few days?
她不想讓我知道
She didn't want me to know
她也不想告訴我
and she didn't want to tell me.
為什麼
Why?
我們要被圍堵了
We're gonna get swarmed.
過載槍上的供能線圈
Overload the charging coil.
你們跟我們走
You will come with us.
謝謝你
Thank you.
你是誰呢
Uh, who are you?
拿著裂解槍的人
The one holding a disruptor.
走我前面
Ahead of me!
要是走錯一步 你們就都得死
One wrong step and you both die.
好吧
Okay.
至少你不會生吞活剝了我們
At least you're not trying to eat us.
往前走
Forward.
可多虧你把它們搞醒了
Thanks for waking them up.
它們數量太多了
There are too many!
那些是力場發生器
Those are forcefield emitters.
控制台就在正中央
The console's dead center!
約瑟夫
Joseph?!
我們能試著把他們引開穿梭機
We could try luring them away from your shuttle,
然後關閉力場逃離
and then lowering the field,
但我們需要武器
but we need weapons.
克里斯
Chris!
我真是嘴欠才找你合作
I walked right into that one.
你到底是誰
Who are you?
先說說你是誰吧
First, we talk about you.
我不得不說 當你們的穿梭機越過邊界時
I have to say, when your shuttle crossed the treaty line,
我簡直難以置信
I couldn't believe it.
我還以為是我的維瑞迪姆定位器壞了
I thought my viridium tracker was broken.
你在追蹤他?
You were tracking him?
下次隆'戈維亞人請你喝酒的時候
When a R'ongovian offers you a drink,
記得別吃掉裡面的橄欖
never eat the olives.
現在你找到我了 但為什麼
Now you found me. Why?
你沒有看見嗎
Do you not see a reflection?
一束來自宿敵的目光
The gaze of an old enemy?
我殺了太多克林貢人
I have killed too many Klingons
以至於我都不知道你來自哪個家族
to know which house you're from.
我是拜莎
I am Bytha.
達克'拉赫的女兒 拉烏爾家族的冠軍戰士
Daughter of Dak'Rah, champion of House Rah'Ul.
拉赫大使的女兒
Ambassador Rah's daughter.
約瑟夫·姆'本加
Joseph M'Benga...
我來這是為了讓你為
I am here to make you answer
被你刺殺的克林貢人付出代價
for the Klingon you assassinated.
正在進入肯佛瑞周圍的緩衝區
We are now entering the buffer zone around Kenfori.
這是一種儀式
It's a ritual.
上尉 保持七分之一脈衝推力
Lieutenant, keep the ship at one-seventh impulse,
但也不要空轉
and not a tick over.
高於此速度會暴露我們的位置
Anything above that will give away our position.
遵命 中校 保持速度
Aye, Commander. Maintaining speed.
艦橋呼叫輪機部
Bridge to Engineering.
關閉所有非必要系統
Power down all non-essential systems.
正在接近克林貢戰列巡洋艦 距離兩百公里
Approaching the battle cruiser at 200 kilometers.
有視訊了
I have a visual.
抱歉 龜速之下我很難機動
Sorry. It's hard to maneuver at snail speed.
距離克林貢戰巡一百公里
Battle Cruiser at 100 kilometers.
我們已經遠離克林貢戰巡
We are clear of the Klingon ship.
通訊如何
Comms?
沒有檢測到任何訊息
Not picking up any chatter.
護盾狀態如何
Shields?
仍然關閉 他們看不到我們
Still down. They can't see us.
檢測到低溫凝華現象
Detecting frozen volatiles forming.
建議將速度降至八分之一脈衝
Recommend reducing speed to one-eighth impulse.
預計抵達時間修改為六小時
Amending estimated arrival to six hours.
我們必須相信派克和姆'本加
We'll have to trust that Pike and M'Benga are capable enough
能夠再堅持多一會
to hold down their own a little while longer.
上尉 降至八分之一脈衝推力
Lieutenant, one-eighth impulse.
已減速至八分之一
Slowing to one-eighth.
中校 我檢測到一些信號
Commander, I'm picking up something now.
是一個監測頻率
It's a monitoring frequency.
他們的傳感器正在啟動
Their sensors are activating.
他們正在將傳感陣列瞄向我艦
They're turning their array toward our ship.
中校 我想我們被發現了
Commander, I think we've been spotted.
沒事的 我會活下來
It's fine. I'll survive.
夠了 離開他
Enough. Leave him.
冤有頭 債有主 饒了我的朋友吧
Your grievance is with me. Spare my friend.
你錯了
You are wrong.
我的冤一直在我父親身上
My grievance has always been with my father,
他是帝國的叛徒
traitor to the empire.
你不是來為他報仇的?
You're not here to avenge him?
他是個戰犯
He was a war criminal
也是投降聯邦的走狗
and a lapdog to the Federation.
死有餘辜
I welcomed his death.
原來是克林貢人的血仇
A Klingon blood feud.
達克'拉赫讓我們家族蒙羞
Dak'Rah brought shame to our family name.
因為他的罪
For his sins,
我們家族受盡屈辱
our house has been subject to discommendation.
族人被疏遠 血統被唾棄
We are shunned, our bloodline spat upon.
甚至 為了包船來這裡 我不得不卑躬屈膝
I had to grovel just to charter a ship here.
只有一種方法可以恢復我們的名譽
There was one way to restore our name.
親手暗殺我的父親
Assassinate my father.
可惡的是 你先殺掉了他
Only, you got to him first.
好吧
Okay.
我們需要保持冷靜
We need to stay calm.
她認為殺了我
She thinks killing me
會以某種方式恢復她的榮譽
will somehow restore her honor.
除非我手刃刺殺我父親的刺客
Our name remains soiled
否則我們的家族仍將蒙羞
unless I kill my father's assassin.
儀式戰鬥?
Ritual combat?
戰鬥至死?
To the death?
他沒有暗殺拉赫
He didn't assassinate Rah.
他的行為是出於自衛
He acted in self-defense.
這個人類說的是實話嗎
Does this human speak the truth?
你的戰士時代已經過去了嗎
Are your warrior days behind you?
我只問你一次
I will only ask you once.
你真的暗殺了我父親嗎
Did you assassinate my father?
他們把我們掃描了個遍
Their scanners are all over us.
-烏乎拉 -還是什麼也沒有
- Uhura. - Still nothing.
克林貢人沒有回應
The Klingons aren't responding.
繼續嘗試
Keep trying.
告訴他們我們來這裡執行救援任務
Inform them that we are here on a rescue mission.
我們並沒有著陸意圖
We are not attempting to land.
他們還沒有升起護盾
They haven't raised shields yet,
但我建議趁我們還有機會 升起護盾
but I recommend raising ours while we have the chance.
不行 這樣會釋放錯誤的信號
No, that sends the wrong message.
為什麼要關心他們的看法
Why do we care what they think?
這毫無意義 如果他們
This is pointless. If they...
說完你的想法 上尉
Finish your thought, Lieutenant.
我只是認為我們已經越過了外交能解決的界限
I just think we're past the point of diplomacy.
你認為向我表達這種擔憂是明智的嗎
And you thought it wise to express that concern to me
鑑於我們正在執行命令的過程中?
in the middle of executing orders?
克林貢艦船護盾已升起
克林貢戰巡正在升起護盾並逼近
The Klingons are raising shields and closing in.
中校 是時候交戰了
Commander, time to engage.
執行規避機動 奧特加斯 看你了
Evasive maneuvers. Ortegas, you're up.
樂意之至
Gladly.
告訴她真相
Just tell her the truth.
我暗殺了拉赫
I assassinated Rah.
-約瑟夫 -我本可以阻止自己
- Joseph... - I could have stopped it.
但這個大屠殺兇手給了我
But a mass murderer gave me
殺死他的機會
the opportunity to kill him.
我如此做了
And I did.
自願的
Willingly.
如果再有機會 我還會如此
I would do it again.
所以 沒錯
So yes.
他的性命 由我奪取
His blood is on my hands.
這是不光彩的嗎
Was that dishonorable?
我不清楚
I don't know.
但我清楚 那是正義
But there was justice.
我撒謊 是為了掩護
I lied to protect
那個仍潛藏於我內心的野獸
the monster that still lives inside me.
若有需要 我會讓他重拾鋒鏑
Should the day come when he is needed again.
把刀拿起來
Pick up the blade.
直面我
And face me.
約瑟夫
Joseph.
別這樣
Don't do this.
我包裡有一個給你的醫療包
There is a med kit for you in my bag.
找到辦法離開這個遺棄星球
Find your way off this forsaken planet,
然後把花帶給巴特爾艦長
and get the flower to Batel.
查普爾護士和史波克那裡有我的實驗記錄
Chapel and Spock have my lab notes.
一定有其他方法
There has to be another way.
夠了
Enough!
是時候了 你死我活
It is time for one of us to die.
我已經準備好面對我的命運了
I am ready to face my destiny.
你呢
Are you?
上面沾有我父親的血
This holds the blood of my father.
把他纏在手上
It binds us.
直到它沾滿敗者的鮮血
Until it is stained with the blood of the vanquished.
不
No!
你不能棄權
You cannot forfeit!
太遲了
Too late.
我今天不需要釋放野獸出來
I do not need the monster today.
輕饒我命
By sparing my life,
是對我的命運下了詛咒 比死了還糟糕
you damn me to a fate worse than death.
這力場要支撐不住了
That field's about to come down.
斯坎內爾中尉 還有多久
Lieutenant Scannell, time?
四秒後進入大氣熱層
Thermospheric entry in four seconds.
外部氣體壓縮到80%
Outer gas compression is at 80%.
所以我們基本上算是撞向一堵磚牆
So basically we're flying into a brick wall.
別亂想了 堅守崗位
Don't think about it, just hang on.
傳送室呼叫艦橋
Transporter to Bridge.
你們必須立刻關閉引擎
You need to cut engine power now!
如果你們不補償行星引力
If you don't compensate for planetary gravity,
船會散架的
we will come apart.
收到 中尉
Copy, Lieutenant.
你繼續嘗試獲取傳送信號
You work on getting us that transporter signal.
佩利亞早就警告過你別逞強
Pelia warned you not to volunteer.
現在好了 說出去的話就像潑出去的水
And now you actually have to do what you promised.
力場重新上線了 但是它撐不了太久
The field is back up, but it won't hold much longer!
目前你殺了一個
You got one.
你還有心情記分啊
You're keeping score?
聽著
Listen, uh...
我們合作 就能都活著逃出去
we work together, we all get out alive.
衝我來
你們這些骯髒的塔格獸
她在吸引喪屍的注意
She's drawing their attention.
為什麼
Why?
通過犧牲她自己
By sacrificing herself,
她會光榮地死去
she chooses an honorable death.
但是沒有人會知道
But no one will ever know.
她會知道
She will know.
我會知道
I will know.
願斯托沃寇歡迎你
May Sto-vo-kor welcome you.
快走 到穿梭機上去
Come on, let's get to the shuttle.
甲板重力層失效
輪機室發出警告
Alert from Engineering!
人工重力正在失效
Artificial gravity is failing
慣性阻尼器效能僅剩20%
and inertial dampeners are at 20%.
如果我們不讓它重新上線
If we don't get it back up...
奧特加斯 你能穩定我們的軌道嗎
Ortegas, can you stabilize us?
稍等
In a minute.
傳送室呼叫艦橋
Transport to Bridge.
在艦船軌道塌陷時 很難保持模式完整性
It's a little hard to maintain pattern integrity in orbital collapse.
你們能不能稍微開穩一點
Can you maybe give me a smidge less turbulence?
斯考特 你知道怎麼重新穩定軌道嗎
Mr. Scott, any ideas on how to re-stabilize?
試試交替啟動脈衝引擎
Try firing impulse thrusters in an alternating pattern.
先啟動輔助引擎 再啟動主引擎
Auxiliary first, then the main.
我要開始傳送了
I'm gonna energize.
我真心希望自己不要把
I really hope I don't scramble
艦長和姆'本加醫生混在一起了
the captain and Dr. M'Benga up.
傳送室呼叫艦橋
Transport to Bridge,
艦長和醫官已經傳送登艦
we have the captain and doctor on board.
幹得好 斯考提 我們現在維持在軌道上
Good one, Scotty. We're maintaining orbit now.
中校 我們的通訊受到干擾
Commander, I'm getting interference on our comms.
有東西在阻塞我們的通訊
Something's jamming us.
來源不是星塵帶
It's not from the dust belt.
打開艦尾視訊
Aft viewscreen.
他們正在進入攻擊陣位
They're on an attack course.
奧特加斯
Ortegas?
馬上就好
Already on it.
吃我們的尾氣去吧
Say hi to our dust.
恭喜 各位
Congratulations, everyone.
艾麗卡 相當精彩的飛行
Erica... stellar flying.
但下次別這麼做了
But never do that again.
艦長個人日誌 補充
Captain's personal log, supplemental.
我們已經帶著一朵奇美拉之花
We have returned from our away mission
從外遣任務歸來
with a single Chimera Blossom.
一旦史波克完成了化合物的合成
Once Spock synthesizes its chemical compounds,
瑪麗就可以開始接受新療法了
Marie's new therapy can begin.
我好奇這個激進的療法
I wonder what effects this radical treatment
對她會有什麼效果
will have on her.
你會上報我的行徑嗎
Are you going to turn me in?
你擔心我會嗎
Are you worried I will?
那取決於我在跟誰說話
That depends on who I'm talking to right now.
是我的朋友
My friend...
還是我的艦長
or my captain?
我理解你為什麼有些事
Look, I understand why you didn't tell me
不肯告訴我了
certain things, huh?
我只希望我能早些知道
I just wish I had known some of them sooner.
按照官方說法
Officially, there was
不存在前往肯佛瑞星的任務
no mission to Kenfori.
所以 那裡什麼也沒有發生
So, nothing happened there.
我沒有什麼報告需要提交
I don't have any report to file.
但是如果假設
But if you did,
你提交了報告
hypothetically,
裡面會怎麼說
what would it say?
會說 有人用刀架在我喉嚨上
That I had a knife to my throat and
你為了救我 編了一個故事
you told a story to save my life.
那就是事情的經過 有異議嗎
That's what happened, wouldn't you agree?
沒有
I would.
你不是一頭野獸 約瑟夫
You're not a monster, Joseph.
只是一個普通人
Just a man.
更是我的朋友
And my friend.
怎麼了 你想聊聊嗎
What's up? You wanted to chat?
請就座 上尉
Have a seat, Lieutenant.
感覺 很正式啊
Oh, this feels, uh, official.
正好在0240時
At precisely 0240 hours,
當我嚴令你保持脈衝引擎推力在八分之一時
you pushed the engines to one-sixth impulse power,
你把它開到了六分之一推力
when I gave you strict orders to keep us at one-eighth.
我在試圖躲避小行星
I was trying to dodge tiny asteroids.
我們當時都很緊張
We were all on edge.
我可能有點手滑了
My finger might have slipped a little.
我相信對一般舵手來說
A reasonable error by the standards
這是個合情合理的錯誤
I hold most helm officers to.
但你不是一般的舵手
But you're not most helm officers.
你不會犯這樣的錯誤
You don't make mistakes like that.
除非你是有意為之
Unless they're intentional.
你逼我做出決定
You forced my hand.
你開得剛好快到能讓我們被克林貢人發現
You flew just fast enough for us to be spotted by the Klingons,
所以我別無選擇 只能轉而執行你的計劃
so I'd have no choice but to switch over to your plan.
看著我的眼睛
Look me in the eye
告訴我 我想錯了
and tell me I'm wrong.
你打算讓派克和姆'本加
You were going to leave Pike and M'Benga
被困在下面六個小時
stranded for six hours.
我們都知道克林貢人不收俘虜
We all know the Klingons don't take prisoners.
你可以不同意我的決策
Disagree with me all you want.
但不是你來做出決策
It's not your call to make.
你知道六個小時能發生什麼嗎
Do you know what could happen in six hours?
對你的遭遇 我感到很遺憾
I'm sorry about what happened to you, Erica.
但是我不能讓這些事影響你的判斷
But I can't have it affect your judgment.
那是個錯誤
It was a mistake.
我能處理好它
I can get a handle on it.
你最好能
You better.
派克和姆'本加當時正準備開穿梭機逃走
Pike and M'Benga were about to escape in a shuttle.
你耍的花招不必要地威脅到了
So your maneuver endangered
艦上每一個人的安全
everyone on the ship unnecessarily.
我並沒有想危及他們
I never meant to do that.
我知道
I know.
但是你抗命是有後果的
But there are consequences for insubordination.
我會把你從輪班表上撤下
I'm pulling you from the duty roster.
兩週時間
Two weeks.
在此期間內 你需要向准尉報道
In that time, you'll have to report to the warrant officer
進行指揮體系訓練
for Chain-of-Command training.
我可以離開了嗎 長官
Am I dismissed, sir?
艾麗卡
Erica.
什麼事 長官
Yes, sir?
這種事不能再發生了
This can't ever happen again.
你明白嗎
You do realize that, right?
我明白
I do.
而且我很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
嘿
Hey.
你的腿怎麼樣了 我聽說你受傷了
How's your leg? I heard you got hurt.
沒事了
It's fine.
我想知道為什麼船上除了我以外
I want to know why everyone else on the ship
所有人都知道這件事
seems to know but me.
當那植物把你和幾乎殺死你的物種
Do you have any idea what could happen?
融合在一起的時候
When that plant fuses you with the species
你知道後果可能有多嚴重嗎
that nearly killed you already?
我清楚所有的風險
I know all the risks and...
但我不在乎
I don't care.
你對我說謊了
Fine, you lied to me.
我從來沒對你說過謊
I never lied to you.
那你為什麼不告訴我
Then why didn't you tell me?
原因在於你
Because of you.
因為這件事 因為我已經沒有餘裕去顧慮
Because of this, because I don't have the space to worry
我的死會如何讓你難過
about how my dying hurts your feelings.
克里斯
Chris?
你還有好幾天時間
You had days and...
但你做出了我能想像的
you made what I can only imagine
你人生中最艱難的決定
is the hardest decision of your life.
我卻沒參與其中
But I wasn't a part of it.
是的 因為這與你無關
Yeah, because it wasn't about you.
我只希望我有機會能說出所有該說的話
I just wish I'd have had the opportunity to be able to say
有機會告訴你 我會無條件支持你
all the right things, to tell you I'd be there no matter what.
無論你做了什麼決定
No matter what choice you made.
如果真是那樣就好了
And that would've been nicer.
但是你知道嗎 你我都心知肚明
But you know what, we both know you and we know
你一定會堅持要我們尋找別的辦法
that you would have demanded we find another way.
然而並沒有別的辦法了
And there is no other way.
我很害怕 克里斯
I'm scared, Chris.
嘿 過來
Hey, come here.
我知道
I know, I know.
我也很害怕
I'm scared, too.